# Erik Rasmussen

**Software Engineer** 

**Application Developer** 

458 NF Delaware Ave. Apt 416. Ankeny, IA 50021

(+1) 515-782-2960

■ecr.referee@hotmail.com

■ unstoppablemango

## **Summary**

Current Application Developer at Kum & Go in Des Moines. 4 years experience specializing in full stack development with a focus on backend systems and architecture. Passion programmer, hobby sysadmin, and Linux enthusiast. Interested in complex problem-solving and procuring the right tools for the job.

#### **Skills**

**DevOps** Azure, Azure DevOps, Docker, Jenkins **Back-end** ASP.NET Core, MVC, gRPC

Front-end Angular, Blazor, HTML5, SASS

**Programming** C#, Typescript, SQL, Node.js, Java, C++/C

# **Work Experience**

Kum & Go

Application Developer

Jan. 2018 - Present

- Developed a food ordering management solution for store associates to track and prioritize orders submitted via mobile and web applications
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Azure Pipelines for applications ranging from console batch applications to containerized Docker web services.
- · Designed and developed the service architecture for a cloud based enterprise food menu management solution in Azure.
- · Upgraded numerous legacy applications to run more efficiently and effectively on modern technologies such as .NET Core.
- · Worked with 3rd party vendors to design, develop, and deploy a cloud based mobile food ordering platform.

# **Principal Financial Group**

Des Moines, IA

Application Developer Intern

Jan. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Implemented decision making and process improvements to applications in the underwriting process pipeline.
- Refactored and re-structured legacy insurance policy applications to improve overall system performance.
- Introduced new integration testing practices for Java REST APIs using mock REST clients and re-usable Docker test environments.
- · Deployed automated CI/CD pipelines for Java Spring web services on WebSphere using Jenkins.

Kum & Go West Des Moines, IA

Application Developer Intern

Jan. 2016 - May 2017, Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Implemented a customer data management tool for the Customer Relations team built on AngularJS and backed by an ASP.NET REST API.
- · Automated processes for updating and managing customer rewards program information.
- · Responded to requests for IT assistance from the Customer Relations team.

#### **University of Wisconsin Platteville**

Platteville, WI

Peer Tutor Sep. 2015 - May 2016

- Initiated one-on-one review sessions with students
- Guided class activities and assignments
- · Managed a computer lab to assist with student education.

### **Education**

## **University of Wisconsin Platteville**

**B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING** 

Platteville, Wisconsin Sep. 2013 - Dec. 2017

Dean's Honours List